<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Random thought from a compiler engineer.</title>
    <link>https://hub.zhox.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Random thought from a compiler engineer.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 07:14:25 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hub.zhox.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The easiest way to setup a Haskell environment on Windows</title>
      <link>https://hub.zhox.com/posts/introducing-haskell-dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 07:14:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hub.zhox.com/posts/introducing-haskell-dev/</guid>
      <description>What is chocolatey Windows has had quite a push lately to provide script-able ways to install packages. One such attempt that has gained quite a lot of traction is Chocolatey (https://chocolatey.org/). Chocolatey&amp;rsquo;s populary is quickly growing.
Chocolatey is supported out of the box in all major cloud CI services including AppVeyor, CircleCI, Travis CI and Azure Pipelines. It&amp;rsquo;s also supported by full system building software such as BoxStarter that are used by companies to provision new machines and also supported by system management software such as Puppet and Ansible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bypassing MAX_PATH Limit with GHC on Windows</title>
      <link>https://hub.zhox.com/posts/bypassing-max_path-limit-on-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 23:49:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hub.zhox.com/posts/bypassing-max_path-limit-on-windows/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: GHC 8.10+ Will ship with a custom GCC+Binutils bindist that will remove the MAX_PATH limitation to files. The GHC binaries themselves must still be in installed in a path shorter than MAX_PATH. GHC 8.6 and GHC 8.8 are also supported if installed via chocolatey by installing the extension ghc-jailbreak. For cabal to work correctly you need a cabal compiled with GHC 8.6+, on chocolatey this means cabal 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why doesn&#39;t GHCi on Windows find my DLL</title>
      <link>https://hub.zhox.com/posts/why-doesnt-ghc-on-windows-find-my-dll/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 10:11:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hub.zhox.com/posts/why-doesnt-ghc-on-windows-find-my-dll/</guid>
      <description>You have a new package you want to try out. You try to install the package only to be greeted with
GHCi, version 8.2.2: http://www.haskell.org/ghc/ :? for help &amp;lt;command line&amp;gt;: user specified .o/.so/.DLL could not be loaded (addDLL: my-cool-library or dependencies not loaded. (Win32 error 126)) Whilst trying to load: (dynamic) my-cool-library Additional directories searched: (none)  by GHCi. Confused you look into your libraries folder and see my-cool-library-7.dll. Why is the file name incorrect?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haskell &amp; AppVeyor Chocolatey Introduction</title>
      <link>https://hub.zhox.com/posts/chocolatey-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 13:14:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hub.zhox.com/posts/chocolatey-introduction/</guid>
      <description>For those who are unaware, Windows has had quite a push lately to provide script-able ways to install packages. One such attempt that has gained quite a lot of traction is Chocolatey https://chocolatey.org/.
Chocolatey also contains some of my own packages for installing GHC and cabal (along with packages to fully automate setting up a GHC dev environment etc, more on these at a later date).
The GHC package https://chocolatey.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>